<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-25T11:27:31-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Scott Birdsey</title><subtitle>Hey test
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Thoughts on becoming a web professional</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writes/thoughts-on-becoming-a-web-professional" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts on becoming a web professional" /><published>2018-01-22T11:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-22T11:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writes/thoughts-on-becoming-a-web-professional</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writes/thoughts-on-becoming-a-web-professional">&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;A family member recently contacted me, expressing a desire for a career-change from the restaurant business to working on the web. He shared with me a local university program he was considering, and wondering my thoughts on it. I, uh, gave him much more than that. Below is my response, something that I think could be useful to others that are curious about working on the web&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, I’d love to give some feedback. I’ll keep it as brief as I can. But it’s not going to be brief. There’s a lot to unpack, because the topic is close to me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think firstly, there’s some good news: it’s important to note that web design and development is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in fact IT, but a creative service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IT’s domain includes disciplines like network configuration, server administration, IE, plugging things into each other and making them work. To me, that has always sounded like an ocean of boring!
Working in software or on the web, on the other hand, you’re creating things for customers to solve problems with. Much more exciting and rewarding for artistic types like us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second: these classes look similar to the program I did at SUNY. It looks to generally cover a wide range of work one might do on the web - design, development, and working with assets like images or video. You can specialize in one of these disciplines, or be a hybrid, depending on what you want for yourself. I have a peer who runs a business as a web designer - she writes almost no code, contracting out someone like me to turn her designs into actual webpages. I have another peer who runs a business as a developer - she works almost exclusively using an open-source website framework called &lt;a href=&quot;http://drupal.org&quot;&gt;Drupal&lt;/a&gt;, and will partner with a designer when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a hybrid of the two, which is great because I love the experience of building something from the ground up. If I don’t feel like I’m involved in the big picture of a project, I tend to get bored. The problem there is that it can be difficult to be a master of any one thing, and indeed, it has taken me about ten years of self-development to start to feel really confident on the design side of the “coin”. &lt;em&gt;Each web professional will find fulfillment on their own terms&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brings me to my last point: these classes should give you a foundation of knowledge to start with, but there’s going to be a lot of fluff that you will not use, too. I would argue that this is because formalized education generally doesn’t move fast enough to keep up with the current stack of practices, standards, and tools that are used on the web. Imagine when the printing press was first invented - it was such a new medium that the best way of learning how to approach it was likely to apprentice with someone, or to experiment on your own. Same with the web - it’s brand new and its functionalities grow everyday. I see a few “red flags” in those course descriptions - &lt;em&gt;Actionscript&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Dreamweaver&lt;/em&gt; - these are obsolete tools that no web professional has used for many years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I did the SUNY program, it was the same. I obtained the piece of paper to get me my job, but much of what I’d learned was irrelevant (I’d been working my job as an intern, and they refused to hire me full-time unless I had a college degree). What I found was that the real learning happens by doing, and by learning what other web folks are doing. It’s a tight-knit community to other creative services, comparatively, again due to its infancy as a medium. That’s where the real learning will happen. So my guess would be that the program will give you a great base to get you started - but be aware that it won’t necessarily always be in touch with the present-day culture of web folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you go for it - it’s a profession that consistently rewards creativity, empathy, and critical thinking - qualities you have no shortage of! I just got off a remote call with a company I work with in Minnetonka, presenting an HTML prototype of a building energy modeling app to one of their executives. I had the luxury of designing and building that prototype all on my own terms, and walking that executive through the various design decisions that I believe will make the product successful. As someone that likes to build things and think critically, it’s enormously fulfilling for me to do something like that, and to know that my work will now be handed off to the company’s software team to turn it into a fully functioning application that people around the country will use.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web design" /><summary type="html">A family member recently contacted me, expressing a desire for a career-change from the restaurant business to working on the web. He shared with me a local university program he was considering, and wondering my thoughts on it. I, uh, gave him much more than that. Below is my response, something that I think could be useful to others that are curious about working on the web</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">8 More Secrets of the Cyclocross Privateer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writes/8-more-secrets-of-the-cyclocross-privateer" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="8 More Secrets of the Cyclocross Privateer" /><published>2017-10-31T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-31T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writes/8-more-secrets-of-the-cyclocross-privateer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writes/8-more-secrets-of-the-cyclocross-privateer">&lt;p&gt;Part of the fun of cyclocross is the many dimensions of skill and preparedness it takes to win, or even do well. I love that part. The other part I love is its communal nature, which I think is probably extra strong here in the backwoods of America (the European lowlands being the nexus of the culture). To that end, enjoy some free tips I’ve picked up along the way. They run the full gamut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;center big&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/kmc2017.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Dry and hot racing at KMC this year (with a dubiously bloody finger?) &lt;em&gt;Photo: Brian Wood&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-glue-some-tire-on-the-bottom-of-your-left-shoe&quot;&gt;1. Glue some tire on the bottom of your left shoe.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cycle-smart.com/cyclocross-camps/&quot;&gt;Adam Myerson’s excellent cross camp&lt;/a&gt; teaches riders to dismount by unclipping the left foot &lt;em&gt;one crank revolution before&lt;/em&gt; unclipping the right foot. Tire tread epoxied on the foot sole behind the cleat gives your foot a nice snug grip - you can even pedal that way. Generally, this will set you up for a more bullet-proof and faster dismount. It’s been working out great particularly when planks are set up on a straightaway, giving me time to execute the most perfect and speedy form that I can. Even if you don’t do this, why not glue some tire on your shoe? You never know when you’ll want to pedal unclipped. The tire tread makes this possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-check-your-brake-pads-use-the-right-brake-pads&quot;&gt;2. Check your brake pads. Use the right brake pads.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special Agent Dale Cooper advises: “Every day, once a day, give yourself a little present.” To that end, I’ve been conducting a much more thorough bike inspection following race days this year, even pulling out calipers to check brake pads if I feel the need &lt;em&gt;(you want at least 2.5mm of material including the backing plate, on a SRAM Force pad)&lt;/em&gt;. Did you know brake pad material can be a big thing in cyclocross? At &lt;a href=&quot;https://topshots.smugmug.com/2017/BCA-Cyclocross-2017/i-NP97z5c&quot;&gt;BCA Cyclocross this year&lt;/a&gt;, I destroyed my organic pads after the first two laps of racing, due to all the mud and water. I’ve since purchased a separate set of sintered pads, which I plan to swap in conditions like these, while cheaper organic pads will be used the rest of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-mini-tire-pressure-checker--pump-on-prerides&quot;&gt;3. Mini tire pressure checker &amp;amp; pump on prerides.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dont keep a full on notebook of pressures I run at races or anything intense like that, but I find it really useful to always start with the same pressure, and adjust from there. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gravelbike.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/gauges-composite.jpg&quot;&gt;This mini pressure checker&lt;/a&gt; - while not as cool as the hashtag-pro Craftsmen gun - is cheap and works great. It can be found pretty easily online. When I pre-ride, I carry it with a mini pump, on the offchance I want to make fast adjustments. I’ve seen a few mini pumps that include a gauge in them, but this is cheap and does the job well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-grab-your-front-brake-to-pop-your-downtube-up-for-a-bike-shoulder&quot;&gt;4. Grab your front brake to pop your downtube up for a bike shoulder.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned this nifty little trick from the badonkers-ly skilled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/iamscottsmith/&quot;&gt;Scott Smith&lt;/a&gt; from JAM Fund. There’s plenty of techniques (and variants upon on those techniques to shoulder a bike), and obviously it’s preference. Me, I tend to grab my downtube and hoist the bike onto the shoulder. In some conditions, giving the front brake a squeeze works great for getting the downtube closer to my hand. Obviously, this is more of a slow-speed trick, and you can’t do it if you’re a brake-swapper (some racers like to put their rear brake on the left hood to safely scrub speed before a dismount).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-pull-your-crank-after-wet-races&quot;&gt;5. Pull your crank after wet races.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this common knowledge? I picked it up from the amazing Bike Shop CX podcast on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wideanglepodium.com/category/bike-shop-cx/&quot;&gt;Wide Angle Podium network&lt;/a&gt;. If it’s really wet, I do it, and leave it overnight. It’s fun to sweat things like this - I didn’t used to be that guy. I’m glad I’m that guy now. The guy that makes time for these matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-core-work-is-the-best-work&quot;&gt;6. Core work is the best work.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a sensitive lower back from a distant motorcycle accident, and used to just generally sometimes feel beat up after a cross race, but that no longer happens now after keeping up with ten-minute core workouts on weekdays. Other than a much more resolute body that can take the bumpy stuff in stride, my sprints feel like a much more connected effort of my upper and lower body. Helen Wyman &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BYBP_NLguAS/?taken-by=cxhelen&quot;&gt;recently shared her core exercise regimen&lt;/a&gt;, and mine are about the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;7-defend-against-the-mid-season-cold&quot;&gt;7. Defend against the mid season cold.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see a lot of people getting sick when November starts to roll around. To that end, this year I’ve been drinking Emergen-C with the same tenacity that the average American drinks soda. Like, twice a day. I had a minor head cold for one weekend, but was able to keep it from getting any worse, so I think it’s worth it. Oh, and I buy the CVS version of Emergen-C. Same stuff, lower price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;8-whats-next&quot;&gt;8. What’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All is well in my world and I am safe. What’s next?” Even the most chill of all the bike racers can plummet down a mental hole when the going gets rough. I reckon that’s particularly true in cyclocross, where there can be drama waiting around every corner. Keep that mantra in mind for when it all gets upside down. My own coach, Andy Ruiz, has similar words to say: “never, ever, quit!””&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="bike racing" /><summary type="html">Part of the fun of cyclocross is the many dimensions of skill and preparedness it takes to win, or even do well. I love that part. The other part I love is its communal nature, which I think is probably extra strong here in the backwoods of America (the European lowlands being the nexus of the culture). To that end, enjoy some free tips I’ve picked up along the way. They run the full gamut.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Weidt Group</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/makes/weidt" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Weidt Group" /><published>2017-07-22T18:48:24-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-22T18:48:24-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/makes/weidt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/makes/weidt">&lt;figure class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/thumbs/weidt.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I carried out the full design and development of The Weidt Group’s corporate website following a wonderful content strategy advisement by twin industry titans &lt;a href=&quot;http://bondartscience.com/&quot;&gt;Bond Art + Science&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://webmeadow.com&quot;&gt;webmeadow&lt;/a&gt;. The site is a lean Wordpress CMS, and a marketing employee is able to manage news, events, and other content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site has a healthy process in place, with regular monthly check-ins with company stakeholders to monitor usage, and iterate on content and design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;Visit theweidtgroup.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EYP</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/makes/eypae" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EYP" /><published>2017-07-22T18:48:24-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-22T18:48:24-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/makes/eypae</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/makes/eypae">&lt;figure class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/thumbs/eypae.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EYP is one of the largest architecture firms in the country, and I have been developing the current incarnation of their website over the past two years. Original design and content strategy were carried out by an incredible collaboration of &lt;a href=&quot;bondartscience.com&quot;&gt;Bond Art + Science&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://webmeadow.com&quot;&gt;webmeadow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://pixelsandpulp.com&quot;&gt;Pixels and Pulp&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ethanmarcotte.com&quot;&gt;Ethan Marcotte&lt;/a&gt;. I took prototypes and built the site out in Drupal 8, and have continued to iterate on both the design and author experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;http://www.eypae.com&quot;&gt;Visit eypae.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Capital Bicycle Racing Club</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/makes/cbrc" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Capital Bicycle Racing Club" /><published>2017-07-22T18:48:24-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-22T18:48:24-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/makes/cbrc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/makes/cbrc">&lt;figure class=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/cbrc-logo.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capital Bicycle Racing Club is a grassroots cycling group in the Capital Region of New York that is over thirty years old. They’ve been around a long time, and had many looks and logos – and are sure to have many more. This is my contribution to that lineage - and the full gamut of products will soon be up - promise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;http://cbrc.cc&quot;&gt;Visit cbrc.cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/cbrc-kits.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Mary Zawacki&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">dr pilates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/makes/dr-pilates" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="dr pilates" /><published>2017-07-22T18:48:24-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-22T18:48:24-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/makes/dr-pilates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/makes/dr-pilates">&lt;p&gt;Drpilates is a Los Angeles pilates studio that contacted me in the months prior to opening up shop. Doug, the owner, was after a website for his business-to-be that would be lean and tailored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/dr-pilates.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I provided a strategy and design for the website, as well as copywriting (eek) - a simple one-page design, with a look and feel based off of his only existing brand assets: a logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would end up building out the design into a responsive and standards-compliant website, with a bit of special code that would display the studio schedule from a third-party web application’s API, called Mindbody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;http://drpilates.com&quot;&gt;Visit drpilates.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Drpilates is a Los Angeles pilates studio that contacted me in the months prior to opening up shop. Doug, the owner, was after a website for his business-to-be that would be lean and tailored.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unknown Pleasures Kneewarmers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/makes/joy-division-kneewarmers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unknown Pleasures Kneewarmers" /><published>2015-07-20T18:48:24-04:00</published><updated>2015-07-20T18:48:24-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/makes/joy-division-kneewarmers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/makes/joy-division-kneewarmers">&lt;figure class=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/joy-division1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always got joy from fashion and gear, so it seems obvious now that cycling was a good fit for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, when I first got a bike and started riding it, I realized after a few group rides that you could be fashionable on a bike, the same way you can in a club or in a supermarket. It wasn’t just exercising in a Planet Fitness. My initial confusion that cycling was a sport, rather than a culture, is comical, now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/joy-division2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ordered twenty of these produced, mostly out of a curiosity as to the process, and an interest in making friends. Unbeknownst to me at the time, several other apparel companies were making jerseys and other items with the pulsar pattern. I’m not sure whether they intended to be a nod to Joy Division. Mine certainly were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the project was a success, because I sold them all, at cost, to new acquaintances, all of which have become friends since.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Night on Buddy’s Bench</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/makes/a-night-on-buddys-bench" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Night on Buddy's Bench" /><published>2015-07-20T18:48:24-04:00</published><updated>2015-07-20T18:48:24-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/makes/a-night-on-buddys-bench</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/makes/a-night-on-buddys-bench">&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/a-night-on-buddys-bench.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anightonbuddysbench.com&quot;&gt;A Night on Buddy’s Bench&lt;/a&gt; is a book about the end of life, experienced by one man. I worked with the author closely to try and create a website that captured the tone and mood of the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is beautifully illustrated with watercolors, so we tried to work those into the website itself as much as possible. Additionally, I created a nifty little audio player for visitors to hear an excerpt of the audiobook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site was created in Wordpress with the intention of the author keeping a blog. To handle the e-commerce, we used a nice lightweight plugin from Shopify, keeping budget down.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>