<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-01T16:22:12-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Scott Birdsey</title><subtitle>Hey test
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Thoughts on becoming a web professional</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writes/thoughts-on-becoming-a-web-professional" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts on becoming a web professional" /><published>2018-01-22T11:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-22T11:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writes/thoughts-on-becoming-a-web-professional</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writes/thoughts-on-becoming-a-web-professional">&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;A family member recently contacted me, expressing a desire for a career-change from the restaurant business to working on the web. He shared with me a local university program he was considering, and wondering my thoughts on it. I, uh, gave him much more than that. Below is my response, something that I think could be useful to others that are curious about working on the web&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, I’d love to give some feedback. I’ll keep it as brief as I can. But it’s not going to be brief. There’s a lot to unpack, because the topic is close to me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think firstly, there’s some good news: it’s important to note that web design and development is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in fact IT, but a creative service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IT’s domain includes disciplines like network configuration, server administration, IE, plugging things into each other and making them work. To me, that has always sounded like an ocean of boring!
Working in software or on the web, on the other hand, you’re creating things for customers to solve problems with. Much more exciting and rewarding for artistic types like us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second: these classes look similar to the program I did at SUNY. It looks to generally cover a wide range of work one might do on the web - design, development, and working with assets like images or video. You can specialize in one of these disciplines, or be a hybrid, depending on what you want for yourself. I have a peer who runs a business as a web designer - she writes almost no code, contracting out someone like me to turn her designs into actual webpages. I have another peer who runs a business as a developer - she works almost exclusively using an open-source website framework called &lt;a href=&quot;http://drupal.org&quot;&gt;Drupal&lt;/a&gt;, and will partner with a designer when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a hybrid of the two, which is great because I love the experience of building something from the ground up. If I don’t feel like I’m involved in the big picture of a project, I tend to get bored. The problem there is that it can be difficult to be a master of any one thing, and indeed, it has taken me about ten years of self-development to start to feel really confident on the design side of the “coin”. &lt;em&gt;Each web professional will find fulfillment on their own terms&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brings me to my last point: these classes should give you a foundation of knowledge to start with, but there’s going to be a lot of fluff that you will not use, too. I would argue that this is because formalized education generally doesn’t move fast enough to keep up with the current stack of practices, standards, and tools that are used on the web. Imagine when the printing press was first invented - it was such a new medium that the best way of learning how to approach it was likely to apprentice with someone, or to experiment on your own. Same with the web - it’s brand new and its functionalities grow everyday. I see a few “red flags” in those course descriptions - &lt;em&gt;Actionscript&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Dreamweaver&lt;/em&gt; - these are obsolete tools that no web professional has used for many years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I did the SUNY program, it was the same. I obtained the piece of paper to get me my job, but much of what I’d learned was irrelevant (I’d been working my job as an intern, and they refused to hire me full-time unless I had a college degree). What I found was that the real learning happens by doing, and by learning what other web folks are doing. It’s a tight-knit community to other creative services, comparatively, again due to its infancy as a medium. That’s where the real learning will happen. So my guess would be that the program will give you a great base to get you started - but be aware that it won’t necessarily always be in touch with the present-day culture of web folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you go for it - it’s a profession that consistently rewards creativity, empathy, and critical thinking - qualities you have no shortage of! I just got off a remote call with a company I work with in Minnetonka, presenting an HTML prototype of a building energy modeling app to one of their executives. I had the luxury of designing and building that prototype all on my own terms, and walking that executive through the various design decisions that I believe will make the product successful. As someone that likes to build things and think critically, it’s enormously fulfilling for me to do something like that, and to know that my work will now be handed off to the company’s software team to turn it into a fully functioning application that people around the country will use.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web design" /><summary type="html">A family member recently contacted me, expressing a desire for a career-change from the restaurant business to working on the web. He shared with me a local university program he was considering, and wondering my thoughts on it. I, uh, gave him much more than that. Below is my response, something that I think could be useful to others that are curious about working on the web</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">8 More Secrets of the Cyclocross Privateer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writes/8-more-secrets-of-the-cyclocross-privateer" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="8 More Secrets of the Cyclocross Privateer" /><published>2017-10-31T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-31T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writes/8-more-secrets-of-the-cyclocross-privateer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writes/8-more-secrets-of-the-cyclocross-privateer">&lt;p&gt;Part of the fun of cyclocross is the many dimensions of skill and preparedness it takes to win, or even do well. I love that part. The other part I love is its communal nature, which I think is probably extra strong here in the backwoods of America (the European lowlands being the nexus of the culture). To that end, enjoy some free tips I’ve picked up along the way. They run the full gamut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;center big&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/kmc2017.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Dry and hot racing at KMC this year (with a dubiously bloody finger?) &lt;em&gt;Photo: Brian Wood&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-glue-some-tire-on-the-bottom-of-your-left-shoe&quot;&gt;1. Glue some tire on the bottom of your left shoe.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cycle-smart.com/cyclocross-camps/&quot;&gt;Adam Myerson’s excellent cross camp&lt;/a&gt; teaches riders to dismount by unclipping the left foot &lt;em&gt;one crank revolution before&lt;/em&gt; unclipping the right foot. Tire tread epoxied on the foot sole behind the cleat gives your foot a nice snug grip - you can even pedal that way. Generally, this will set you up for a more bullet-proof and faster dismount. It’s been working out great particularly when planks are set up on a straightaway, giving me time to execute the most perfect and speedy form that I can. Even if you don’t do this, why not glue some tire on your shoe? You never know when you’ll want to pedal unclipped. The tire tread makes this possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-check-your-brake-pads-use-the-right-brake-pads&quot;&gt;2. Check your brake pads. Use the right brake pads.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special Agent Dale Cooper advises: “Every day, once a day, give yourself a little present.” To that end, I’ve been conducting a much more thorough bike inspection following race days this year, even pulling out calipers to check brake pads if I feel the need &lt;em&gt;(you want at least 2.5mm of material including the backing plate, on a SRAM Force pad)&lt;/em&gt;. Did you know brake pad material can be a big thing in cyclocross? At &lt;a href=&quot;https://topshots.smugmug.com/2017/BCA-Cyclocross-2017/i-NP97z5c&quot;&gt;BCA Cyclocross this year&lt;/a&gt;, I destroyed my organic pads after the first two laps of racing, due to all the mud and water. I’ve since purchased a separate set of sintered pads, which I plan to swap in conditions like these, while cheaper organic pads will be used the rest of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-mini-tire-pressure-checker--pump-on-prerides&quot;&gt;3. Mini tire pressure checker &amp;amp; pump on prerides.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dont keep a full on notebook of pressures I run at races or anything intense like that, but I find it really useful to always start with the same pressure, and adjust from there. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gravelbike.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/gauges-composite.jpg&quot;&gt;This mini pressure checker&lt;/a&gt; - while not as cool as the hashtag-pro Craftsmen gun - is cheap and works great. It can be found pretty easily online. When I pre-ride, I carry it with a mini pump, on the offchance I want to make fast adjustments. I’ve seen a few mini pumps that include a gauge in them, but this is cheap and does the job well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-grab-your-front-brake-to-pop-your-downtube-up-for-a-bike-shoulder&quot;&gt;4. Grab your front brake to pop your downtube up for a bike shoulder.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned this nifty little trick from the badonkers-ly skilled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/iamscottsmith/&quot;&gt;Scott Smith&lt;/a&gt; from JAM Fund. There’s plenty of techniques (and variants upon on those techniques to shoulder a bike), and obviously it’s preference. Me, I tend to grab my downtube and hoist the bike onto the shoulder. In some conditions, giving the front brake a squeeze works great for getting the downtube closer to my hand. Obviously, this is more of a slow-speed trick, and you can’t do it if you’re a brake-swapper (some racers like to put their rear brake on the left hood to safely scrub speed before a dismount).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-pull-your-crank-after-wet-races&quot;&gt;5. Pull your crank after wet races.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this common knowledge? I picked it up from the amazing Bike Shop CX podcast on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wideanglepodium.com/category/bike-shop-cx/&quot;&gt;Wide Angle Podium network&lt;/a&gt;. If it’s really wet, I do it, and leave it overnight. It’s fun to sweat things like this - I didn’t used to be that guy. I’m glad I’m that guy now. The guy that makes time for these matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-core-work-is-the-best-work&quot;&gt;6. Core work is the best work.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a sensitive lower back from a distant motorcycle accident, and used to just generally sometimes feel beat up after a cross race, but that no longer happens now after keeping up with ten-minute core workouts on weekdays. Other than a much more resolute body that can take the bumpy stuff in stride, my sprints feel like a much more connected effort of my upper and lower body. Helen Wyman &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BYBP_NLguAS/?taken-by=cxhelen&quot;&gt;recently shared her core exercise regimen&lt;/a&gt;, and mine are about the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;7-defend-against-the-mid-season-cold&quot;&gt;7. Defend against the mid season cold.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see a lot of people getting sick when November starts to roll around. To that end, this year I’ve been drinking Emergen-C with the same tenacity that the average American drinks soda. Like, twice a day. I had a minor head cold for one weekend, but was able to keep it from getting any worse, so I think it’s worth it. Oh, and I buy the CVS version of Emergen-C. Same stuff, lower price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;8-whats-next&quot;&gt;8. What’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All is well in my world and I am safe. What’s next?” Even the most chill of all the bike racers can plummet down a mental hole when the going gets rough. I reckon that’s particularly true in cyclocross, where there can be drama waiting around every corner. Keep that mantra in mind for when it all gets upside down. My own coach, Andy Ruiz, has similar words to say: “never, ever, quit!””&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="bike racing" /><summary type="html">Part of the fun of cyclocross is the many dimensions of skill and preparedness it takes to win, or even do well. I love that part. The other part I love is its communal nature, which I think is probably extra strong here in the backwoods of America (the European lowlands being the nexus of the culture). To that end, enjoy some free tips I’ve picked up along the way. They run the full gamut.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jump Into Cyclocross!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writes/jump-into-cyclocross" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jump Into Cyclocross!" /><published>2017-09-09T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-09T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writes/jump-into-cyclocross</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writes/jump-into-cyclocross">&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;This article was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adksports.com/2017-09-cyclocross&quot;&gt;originally published in ADK Sports&lt;/a&gt;. I wrote it with the intention to try and grab road or mountain cyclists who may be potentially cx converts, or to get casual cx racers motivated for the season. My sincere thanks to ADK Sports for the love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;center big&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/jump-into-cyclocross/1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Placid Planet Cross in Wadhams happens right in the Adirondack Park on November 25. &lt;em&gt;Photo: Shaun Ondak&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#crossiscoming – As I write this in late August, about every other image in my Instagram feed is currently labeled as such. That strange and beautiful thing called cyclocross is upon us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Cross is labeled a niche sport, and understandably so. The average American, no matter how athletically-inclined, is unlikely to have a reference point. We’re working on it. For a convert like myself, there’s no shortage of imagery I can share: bright lycra skinsuits dulled by spatterings of mud, the snaking geometry of course tape through a park, the mad ravings of course announcers calling the action, all saturated in that romantically crisp bliss of Northeast autumn air. And the adrenaline of the race. Oh man, the adrenaline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/jump-into-cyclocross/2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Uncle Sam Grand Prix, part of the NYCROSS Series, takes place October 7-8 in Troy’s Prospect Park. &lt;em&gt;Photo: Mary Zawacki&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s all get on the same page: ‘cross happens in a park, where a course has been constructed out of staked race tape, creating a three-mile loop about the width of a lane of road. Grass, dirt, sand, ruts, off-camber, hairpin turns, and if it rains there’s mud. Later there’s snow. I won’t soon forget the experience of racing a bike in lycra in 25-degree weather at CX Nationals in Hartford, Conn., last year. It all happens with your heart pumping at an unreasonable speed, and a crowd of spectators urging you to go faster, and catch the wheel ahead of you. It’s weird, it’s fun, it’s communal and it’s addictive. The whole race day is a big party, where you can relax and enjoy food and beverages with friends after your race. You need to see it for yourself – good thing there’s YouTube! I highly recommend looking up &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/H9hUiGyw_lg?t=1m28s&quot;&gt;the 2017 Elite Women’s World Championship in Bieles, Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what’s awesome? In upstate New York, we’re in a hotbed of American cross, and 2017 is going to be bigger than ever, with races of every size happening almost every weekend. Get on bikereg.com and see for yourself! If you’re new to the sport and wanting to dip a toe in, most local cycling clubs will have a connection to a local practice or clinic going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;right&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/jump-into-cyclocross/3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Wicked Creepy Cross in Bennington, Vt., features a signature costume lap as a brief respite from the real race action. &lt;em&gt;Photo: Don Massone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grassroots races are the lifeblood of cyclocross, and happen all over our region. Expect most of the fields to peak at about 20 to 30 racers, but expect no shortness of quality or passion in the experience. In the Capital Region and surrounding area, we run the &lt;a href=&quot;http://nycross.com&quot;&gt;NYCROSS Race Series&lt;/a&gt; that’s in its 12th year. The series stretches over the course of the fall: Kirkland Cyclocross on September 9 in Clinton (near Utica); Uncle Sam Cyclocross GP on October 7-8 in Troy; Wicked Creepy Cross on October 29 in Bennington, Vt.; and Bethlehem Cup on November 19 in Delmar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the western New York scene on one side and the masses of New England racers on the other, the NYCROSS races tend to get a nice mash-up of different regional crowds. Each of our courses are like a fine wine, having been aged and perfected over the years, and we couldn’t be prouder of them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But those central and western New Yorkers are doing big things too, and you’ll find no shortage of races from Syracuse to Buffalo. In fact, Rochester is the site of the &lt;a href=&quot;rochestercyclocross.com&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;very first American UCI race on September 9-10 at Genesee Valley Park, and will feature several of the biggest domestic names at the pro level. There’s nothing like watching the pros race on the very same course that you raced on earlier in the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;cidercross.com&quot;&gt;Cider Cross&lt;/a&gt;, which is held outside Syracuse on an apple orchard – what’s more bucolic than that! – will host New York’s annual Cyclocross Championship on November 5 at the Beak &amp;amp; Skiff Apple Orchard, where the coveted NYS Champion jerseys will be awarded for various racing categories by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://nysbra.com&quot;&gt;New York Bicycle Racing Association&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/jump-into-cyclocross/4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Embracing the elements at the 2016 KMC Cross Fest in Thompson, CT. &lt;em&gt;Photo: Jennifer Harvey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings us to New England. I personally will be driving over the Berkshires several times this season to get my legs ripped off by the unbridled talent that comprises New England bike racing culture. Arguably the cradle of American CX, Massachusetts and Connecticut have some major events happening this year that are helping to take the American movement to even greater heights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://kmccrossfest.com&quot;&gt;KMC Cross Fest&lt;/a&gt; on the September 28 to October 1 weekend at the Thompson Speedway in Thompson, Conn. It’s a four-day festival that features Gran Fondo New England, races for everyone, and big vendor presence, KMC is now one of four races selected to be part of a brand new US Cyclocross Cup supported by USA Cycling. This series offers major cash and prestige, so expect pro races for men and women at KMC to be lit! Remember – this isn’t a road race – because it’s on a closed course, spectating a cross race is honestly almost as exhilarating as racing yourself. It hurts a whole lot less, but don’t expect to have much of a speaking voice leftover if it’s a tight race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;right&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/jump-into-cyclocross/5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;NBX, in Warwick, RI: that beach run, tho. &lt;em&gt;Photo: Don Massone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real gran-daddy of them all is Adam Myerson’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://necyclocross.com&quot;&gt;Vittoria Northeast Cyclocross Series&lt;/a&gt;, a four-event series that takes athletes to Gloucester, Mass. on October 14-15; Northampton, Mass. on November 11-12; Suffern, NY on November 18-19; and Warwick, RI on December 2-3. The series has been one of the standard-bearers stateside for years. Learn more at necyclocross.com. With major sponsors onboard, these races will feel like scaled-up versions of their grassroots brethren – the same communal passion, but more of everything – race fields swell to over 100 in a field, courses are more varied, and everyone brings their best legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyclocross is unparalleled in localism and inclusiveness, qualities that are indispensable in this brave new world of fake news and fidget spinners! It’s happening near you in a public park, where you can watch the race unfold all around you. Bring your dogs, bring your kids, and bring some cash for a tasty post-race treat from the local food truck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are hopeful amateurs that treat each race with the seriousness of a moon launch (guilty), and there are characters donning costumes to heckle friends so bring on the LOLs. And hey, riding around on grass means slower speeds than races of the road variety, which means that it’s for all ages, and all levels of sanity. Crashing out in a race hurts substantially less on grass at 10 mph than on pavement at 25 mph – ask me how I know!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="bike racing" /><summary type="html">This article was originally published in ADK Sports. I wrote it with the intention to try and grab road or mountain cyclists who may be potentially cx converts, or to get casual cx racers motivated for the season. My sincere thanks to ADK Sports for the love.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Internal Monologue at the Blunt Park CompEdge Race</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writes/my-internal-monologue-at-the-blunt-park-compedge-race" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Internal Monologue at the Blunt Park CompEdge Race" /><published>2017-08-27T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-27T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writes/my-internal-monologue-at-the-blunt-park-compedge-race</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writes/my-internal-monologue-at-the-blunt-park-compedge-race">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-night-before&quot;&gt;The night before&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, this race predictor thingie doesn’t look bad, I’m predicted at 10th, so maybe I’ll shoot for a top five. And I haven’t seen this course yet, but maybe tenth will give me a first-row callup!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-preride&quot;&gt;The preride&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hmm, woah, this course has a lot of turns in it! The terrain is this weird, loose, loam-ey type stuff. This will be really good cornering experience for me, especially so early in the season, but I’m totally going to fall on this stuff. It reminds me of NBX, and that went &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt;. But stay on the bright side, eh? I mean, it was a genius decision to do the file tread in the rear and the Grifo up front - yeah, the front will help me carve those turns and bring the file tread right through.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-call-up&quot;&gt;The call-up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh hey, everyone is here already…[waits]…okay, the tape is being removed and it’s time for call-ups…wait, what? There’s no call-ups, it’s just a mass start with whomever in front getting to start in front?! How did I miss this?! Was it on the BikeReg page? This is really terrible, I’m way back here in the third row, with about twenty people in front of me. This is a &lt;em&gt;disaster&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-lap&quot;&gt;The first lap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re starting! I’m sprinting well, but the guy in front of me isn’t, and all these people are passing us. I’m going to have to go &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; if I’m going to meet my top five goal. I’m going to start passing people ASAP, even though we’re going into single-track woods.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh yep, I just put down way too much power over this rooted section and yard-saled all over the course! It’s good that my adrenaline is so lit right now that I can’t feel anything! Just get back up and keep fighting, there’s plenty of racing left. But I wonder how much further up the race-leaders are. Will I be able to catch them?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-second-lap&quot;&gt;The second lap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Um, what, my front tire is flat? The tubular I glued last week? &lt;em&gt;Fuck&lt;/em&gt;. I should probably quit now before I damage myself or my bike more. It’d be for the best, right? But the pit just happened to be right here in front of me, and I did put some spare wheels there, so I may as well swap a wheel and keep going. I can’t quit, that’s not me. Yeah, my goals for today are out the door, but I’m not a wasteful dude – I can just turn this into another awesome learning experience. But also: Is cyclocross just something I’ll never be good at? Should I take up badminton instead? And what about all these long hours of training I’ve done – why am I in the back of the race? This is &lt;em&gt;so unfair&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-finish-line&quot;&gt;The finish line&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Wow, I made it – and those last two laps felt pretty comfortable. It was like I stopped thinking everything except what was right in front of me in the present. That was &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much easier, and it was fun, too – I slowly passed people one by one, but I didn’t make silly mistakes because I was too anxious to pass more. So how can I start focusing on the present from the race start?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-yeah-racing-cross-its-all-mental&quot;&gt;So yeah, racing cross, it’s all mental&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, I’ve read it a zillion times in books, but after today it’s never been more clear that competition is mostly mental, and that life in general is pretty difficult when you’re not living in the present moment. I can see that one setback – not being placed for an ideal start - led me down a path of worry and anxiety. It felt good to air it all out on here though! And that last question – how can I start focusing on the present from the race start – I don’t know the answer, but I’m going to find it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="bike racing" /><summary type="html">The night before</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EYP</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/makes/eypae" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EYP" /><published>2017-07-23T18:48:24-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-23T18:48:24-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/makes/eypae</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/makes/eypae">&lt;p&gt;EYP is one of the largest architecture firms in the country, and I have been developing the current Drupal 8 incarnation of their website over the past two years. Original design, development, and content strategy were carried out by an incredible collaboration of folks put together by Karen McGrane and her &lt;a href=&quot;bondartscience.com&quot;&gt;Bond Art + Science&lt;/a&gt; brand. I took prototypes and built the site out in Drupal 8, and have continued to iterate on both the design and author experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/thumbs/eypae.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web design" /><category term="front-end development" /><category term="Drupal development" /><summary type="html">EYP is one of the largest architecture firms in the country, and I have been developing the current Drupal 8 incarnation of their website over the past two years. Original design, development, and content strategy were carried out by an incredible collaboration of folks put together by Karen McGrane and her Bond Art + Science brand. I took prototypes and built the site out in Drupal 8, and have continued to iterate on both the design and author experience.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Weidt Group</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/makes/weidt" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Weidt Group" /><published>2017-07-22T18:48:24-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-22T18:48:24-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/makes/weidt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/makes/weidt">&lt;p&gt;I carried out the full design and development of The Weidt Group’s corporate website following a wonderful content strategy advisement by twin industry titans &lt;a href=&quot;http://bondartscience.com/&quot;&gt;Bond Art + Science&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://webmeadow.com&quot;&gt;webmeadow&lt;/a&gt;. The site is a very minimal Wordpress setup, and a marketing employee is able to manage news, events, and other content. Three years later, we still have a healthy process in place, with regular monthly check-ins with company stakeholders to monitor usage, and iterate on content and design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/thumbs/weidt.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web design" /><category term="front-end development" /><category term="Wordpress development" /><summary type="html">I carried out the full design and development of The Weidt Group’s corporate website following a wonderful content strategy advisement by twin industry titans Bond Art + Science and webmeadow. The site is a very minimal Wordpress setup, and a marketing employee is able to manage news, events, and other content. Three years later, we still have a healthy process in place, with regular monthly check-ins with company stakeholders to monitor usage, and iterate on content and design.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Capital Bicycle Racing Club</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/makes/cbrc" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Capital Bicycle Racing Club" /><published>2017-07-22T18:48:24-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-22T18:48:24-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/makes/cbrc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/makes/cbrc">&lt;p&gt;Capital Bicycle Racing Club is a grassroots cycling group in the Capital Region of New York that is over thirty years old. They’ve been around a long time, and had many looks and logos – and are sure to have many more. This is my contribution to that lineage - and the full gamut of products will soon be up - promise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-gallery&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/cbrc-logo.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;

	&lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/cbrc-kits.jpg&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Mary Zawacki&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;

	&lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/cbrc-crit2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;

	&lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/cbrc-waterbottles.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;

	&lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/cbrc-tent.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;

	&lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/cbrc-cap.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;




&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="logo design" /><category term="design system" /><category term="apparel design" /><category term="web design" /><category term="front-end development" /><summary type="html">Capital Bicycle Racing Club is a grassroots cycling group in the Capital Region of New York that is over thirty years old. They’ve been around a long time, and had many looks and logos – and are sure to have many more. This is my contribution to that lineage - and the full gamut of products will soon be up - promise!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">dr pilates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/makes/dr-pilates" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="dr pilates" /><published>2017-07-22T18:48:24-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-22T18:48:24-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/makes/dr-pilates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/makes/dr-pilates">&lt;p&gt;Drpilates is a Los Angeles pilates studio that I have served for five years. Initially I provided a strategy and design for the website, as well as copywriting - a simple one-page design, with a look and feel based off of his only existing brand assets: a logo. I ended up building out the design into a responsive and standards-compliant website, with a PHP script that would display the studio schedule from the Mindbody API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/dr-pilates.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web design" /><category term="front-end development" /><summary type="html">Drpilates is a Los Angeles pilates studio that I have served for five years. Initially I provided a strategy and design for the website, as well as copywriting - a simple one-page design, with a look and feel based off of his only existing brand assets: a logo. I ended up building out the design into a responsive and standards-compliant website, with a PHP script that would display the studio schedule from the Mindbody API.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unknown Pleasures Kneewarmers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/makes/joy-division-kneewarmers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unknown Pleasures Kneewarmers" /><published>2015-07-20T18:48:24-04:00</published><updated>2015-07-20T18:48:24-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/makes/joy-division-kneewarmers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/makes/joy-division-kneewarmers">&lt;p&gt;Limited run of twenty produced for friends and myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/joy-division1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/joy-division2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="apparel design" /><summary type="html">Limited run of twenty produced for friends and myself.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Night on Buddy’s Bench</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/makes/a-night-on-buddys-bench" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Night on Buddy's Bench" /><published>2015-07-20T18:48:24-04:00</published><updated>2015-07-20T18:48:24-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/makes/a-night-on-buddys-bench</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/makes/a-night-on-buddys-bench">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anightonbuddysbench.com&quot;&gt;A Night on Buddy’s Bench&lt;/a&gt; is a book about the end of life, experienced by one man. I worked with the author closely to try and create a website that captured the tone and mood of the book. The book is beautifully illustrated with watercolors, so we tried to work those into the website itself as much as possible. Additionally, I created a nifty little audio player for visitors to hear an excerpt of the audiobook. The site was created in Wordpress with the intention of the author keeping a blog. To handle the e-commerce, we used a nice lightweight plugin from Shopify, keeping budget down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/work/a-night-on-buddys-bench.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web design" /><category term="front-end development" /><category term="Wordpress development" /><summary type="html">A Night on Buddy’s Bench is a book about the end of life, experienced by one man. I worked with the author closely to try and create a website that captured the tone and mood of the book. The book is beautifully illustrated with watercolors, so we tried to work those into the website itself as much as possible. Additionally, I created a nifty little audio player for visitors to hear an excerpt of the audiobook. The site was created in Wordpress with the intention of the author keeping a blog. To handle the e-commerce, we used a nice lightweight plugin from Shopify, keeping budget down.</summary></entry></feed>